<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Substratus Blog</title>
        <link>https://www.substratus.ai/blog</link>
        <description>Substratus Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Substratus]]></title>
            <link>https://www.substratus.ai/blog/introducing-substratus</link>
            <guid>https://www.substratus.ai/blog/introducing-substratus</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are excited to introduce Substratus, the open-source cross-cloud substrate for training and serving ML models with an initial focus on Large Language Models. Fine-tune and serve LLMs on your Kubernetes clusters in your cloud.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to introduce Substratus, the open-source cross-cloud substrate for training and serving ML models with an initial focus on Large Language Models. Fine-tune and serve LLMs on your Kubernetes clusters in your cloud.</p><p>Can’t wait? - Get started with our <a href="https://www.substratus.ai/docs/quickstart" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">quick start docs</a> or hop over to our <a href="https://github.com/substratusai/substratus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub repo</a>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-substratus"><strong><em>Why Substratus?</em></strong><a href="#why-substratus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to why-substratus" title="Direct link to why-substratus">​</a></h2><p><strong>Press the fast-button for ML</strong>: Leverage out of the box container images to load a base model, optionally fine-tune with your own dataset and spin up a model server, all without having to write any code.</p><p><strong>Notebook-integrated workflows:</strong> Launch a remote, containerized, gpu-enabled notebook from a local directory with a single command. Develop in the exact same environment as your long running jobs will run in.</p><p><strong>No vendor lock-in</strong>: Substratus is open-source and can run anywhere Kubernetes runs.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Keep company data internal</strong>: Deploy in your cloud account. Training data and inference APIs stay within your company’s network.</p><p><strong>Best practices by default:</strong> Substratus models are immutable and contain information about their lineage. Datasets are imported and snapshotted using off-the-shelf manifests. Training executes in containerized environments, using immutable base artifacts. Inference servers are preconfigured to leverage quantization on supported models. GitOps is built in, not bolted on.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="guiding-principles"><strong><em>Guiding Principles</em></strong><a href="#guiding-principles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to guiding-principles" title="Direct link to guiding-principles">​</a></h2><p>As we continue to develop Substratus, we’re grounded in the following guiding principles:</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1-prioritize-simplicity"><strong>1. Prioritize Simplicity</strong><a href="#1-prioritize-simplicity" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1-prioritize-simplicity" title="Direct link to 1-prioritize-simplicity">​</a></h3><p> We believe the importance of minimizing complexity in software cannot be understated. In Substratus, we will work hard to keep complexity to a minimum as the project grows. The Substratus API currently consists of 4 resource types: Datasets, Models, Servers, and Notebooks. The project currently depends on two cloud services outside of the cluster: a bucket and a container registry (we are working on making these optional too). The project does not (and will never) depend on a web of complex components like Istio.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2-prioritize-ux"><strong>2. Prioritize UX</strong><a href="#2-prioritize-ux" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2-prioritize-ux" title="Direct link to 2-prioritize-ux">​</a></h3><p>We believe a company’s most precious resource is their engineer’s time. Substratus seeks to maximize the productivity of data scientists and engineers through providing a best-in-class user experience. We strive to build a set of well-designed primitives that allow ML practitioners to enter a flow state as they move between importing data, training, and serving models.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="roadmap"><strong><em>Roadmap</em></strong><a href="#roadmap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to roadmap" title="Direct link to roadmap">​</a></h2><p>We are fast at work adding new functionality, focused on creating the most productive and enjoyable platform for ML practitioners. Coming soon:&nbsp;</p><ol><li>Support for AWS and Azure</li><li>VS Code Notebook Integration</li><li>Large-scale distributed training</li><li>ML ecosystem integrations</li></ol><p>Try Substratus today in your GCP project by following the <a href="https://www.substratus.ai/docs/quickstart" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">quick start docs</a>. Let us know what features you would like to see on our <a href="https://github.com/substratusai/substratus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub repo</a> and don’t forget to add a star!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello world</category>
            <category>introduction</category>
            <category>oss launch</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>